once you know what your skill stack is
uh and you're starting to track your
skill stck that means you've done
everything necessary to lead up to that
point so you know what it is that you
need to learn and why you need to learn
it now you need to know that before you
ask the questions about education and
that's what this video is about um
people always start with the wrong
question they start with do I need to
agree and they have no idea what they
want to
do they like I don't know what do you
want to do and there are lots and lots
of videos on that and I this is just
kind of the umbrella video for the for
the Baseline
question discover what education for
yourself is required for your targeted
career for your skill stack the skill
stack that you have set up for yourself
the one that you have already pondered
whe whether you want to do it or not
you've already made contact with
potential employers without seeking
employment just discover what those
rules are you've gone to meetups you
know what the jobs
are and you now have total control of
your education and this is the part
where we then start to talk about
education what type of education formal
education certificates autodidactic
projects that you set up for yourself
all of these educational questions come
after the decision
about what career you want to
do and nobody wants to hear that they
want to they want you know sometimes I
just want to do whatever is going to
give me a job whatever going to get me
money fine but you need to have a
targeted career this is such an
important thing that there are now
universities including the University of
North Carolina um that are
giving scholarships for a gap year to
people before who get into the
University
and they people are applying for what's
called a gap year normally a gap year is
between their first year and set
freshman year and sophomore year
something so they can kind go out into
the world and explore what they want to
do with their
life but we're starting to see some
universities including UNC Charlotte
give scholarships to students who have
gotten into the school who haven't even
attended a single day haven't even
declared a major so that they can go
figure it out you don't need a
scholarship to take a gap year
or however many months you need to
figure it out what is that you want to
do you don't need that you can figure
that out on your own all of that work
that I that we we talked about with
researching and making contact with
employers and and and maybe shadowing
people there's all of these things you
can do that all come from answering one
question what are the
employers that what are the jobs what
are the tasks what are the jobs that
have those tasks who are those employers
How can I talk to them how can I make
contact with them how can I Shadow the
people that are doing those things and
what are the specific skills in my skill
tech for that once you get to that point
you are now free to roam about the cabin
the cabin being the entire industry and
you can walk around and you can see what
was going on out there and then like the
story I told of the the the boy that I
had helped Mentor he knew exactly what
he wanted down to whether or not they
had a certain particular device in their
computer engineering
lab that's how specific his targeted
career path was by the time he even made
a decision to pay a college to go into
the college this is completely flipped
from the concepts of traditional
education where you discover who you are
at a very high price tag in 2024 you
cannot afford to screw around at
$10,000 a year to tr to figure out what
you want to be you need to know before
and by the way some of those times
that's going to mean you don't need a
degree we're going to talk about that so
within the next couple videos that are
related to this are going to be should
you get a computer science degree is it
going to hurt you is it going to help
you what college should you go to should
you go to not should you get certificate
certified should you do you know what
are the job possibilities there's a lot
of stuff out there that you can consider
after that fact um but but yeah and do
you need leak code all right